compareandsave.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy | compareandsave.com

At compareandsave.com we take data protection very seriously and we respect the privacy of each individual that visits our site. This Privacy Policy has been developed to help put your mind at ease and allow you to feel confident that your personal information will always be handled in a private and secure manner.

By using compareandsave.com and our price comparison services you are hereby giving us permission to use your data as detailed in this Privacy Policy. If you do not wish for us to do so then please refrain from using our services.

##  1\. About compareandsave.com

compareandsave.com is a trading name of Freedom Marketing Limited, registered in England (Registration number 05349340) at Colchester Centre, Hawkins Road, Colchester, Essex, CO2 8JX. In this Privacy Policy any use of the words “we”, “us” and “our” means Freedom Marketing Limited. Freedom Marketing Limited complies with and is registered under the data protection laws in the UK.

As required by the Data Protection Act 1998 we follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of your information. Further details can be found at [informationcommissioner.gov.uk](http://www.informationcommissioner.gov.uk/)

For the purposes of the act the data controller is:

**Data Protection Officer  
** **Freedom Marketing Limited  
** **Colchester Centre  
** **Hawkins Road  
** **Colchester  
** **CO2 8JX  
**

##  2\. Information we collect

Freedom Marketing Ltd may collect, store and use the following kinds of information:

  * Information that you provide by filling in our online forms (for tailored product quotes, competition entry or newsletter signup). The provision of our service(s) may also require us to store the information you give us.
  * Fulfilment of your requests by our third party providers – either a broker or an intermediary (Service Provider) – or directly through a provider, such as a credit card issuer, bank or insurer.
  * Details of your visit(s) to our site including traffic source, IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and page views – and the resources that you access.

If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

##  3\. Cookies

In some instances compareandsave.com uses cookie-based technology. A cookie is a text file stored by a web browser, sent by a web server. This ‘cookie’ then enables the web server to track the web browser. We may send cookies to your web browser for the following reasons:

  * Track purchases made for products using links via compareandsave.com
  * Validating competition entries
  * Allow us to identify individual users whilst they are logged in
  * Help us determine products we feel might be of interest to you

Using compareandsave.com will also result in cookies being sent to your browser by third parties.

These include (amongst others):

  * Google Analytics
  * Google Advertising Products
  * Omniture
  * Mediamath
  * Facebook

For further details about our Cookie Policy please click [here](http://www.compareandsave.com/cookie-policy/)

##  4\. Use of Information

We may use your information to:

  * To process a request for a sale, quotation or an application for a product or service made through our Site.
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and third party providers via our site.
  * To allow you to access and use our services
  * Improve your browsing experience by making changes to the website
  * For marketing/remarketing of products and services via digital means (email and SMS) by compareandsave.com and other brands managed by Freedom Marketing Ltd

We may contact you:

  * To ensure you have received the required service from our providers.
  * For marketing/ remarketing of products and services via digital means (email and SMS) by compareandsave.com and other brands managed by Freedom Marketing Ltd
  * To provide un-personalised aggregated data about our users to current and potential advertisers.

**De-registration and un-subscribing from emails**

You may at any time deregister from compareandsave.com email by emailing _optout@freedommarketing.co.uk_. The consequences of deregistration are that your email will be placed in a suppression file and you will not receive any further email communications from Freedom Marketing Ltd.

##  5\. Disclosing Information

By submitting information to comparesave.com, you are consenting for your data to be used by us – and our third party providers. This consent applies to both ordinary personal data and sensitive personal data, such as information about your health, debts, criminal proceedings or convictions.

If you are submitting data on behalf of another individual (for whom you are not considered a legal Guardian), you must get their permission first. This applies to both ordinary and sensitive personal data. In submitting other individual’s details, you are confirming to Freedom Marketing Ltd that you have authorisation and that the individual concerned understands how their information might be used under the terms of this privacy policy.

Please be aware that once you use our site/services, you will be regarded as having given your consent for us to disclose your personal information to the following parties:

  * If you apply for a product or service through our Site, we will need to disclose the information you enter to the relevant Product Provider or Service Provider. This information is necessary to process your purchase or application. The service provider will contact you to deal with your application or enquiry. We will hold all personal information in confidence and only use it to assist you with your purchase or application – with certain exceptions which are detailed in this privacy policy.
  * For the purpose of compliance monitoring by The Financial Conduct Authority, Office of Fair Trading, Information Commissioner and/or other regulatory/governing bodies it is our legal obligation to disclose or share your personal data. This is also the case when we want to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; to protect the rights, property or safety of Freedom Marketing Ltd staff, customers – or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.
  * In the event that your choice of third party provider does not approve your application, or offers a less attractive product or service than you had originally applied for, we will pass on your details to other third parties who might be able to offer a similar or alternative product that meets your criteria.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties if:

  * We buy or sell any business or assets – in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer
  * Please note that when you enter a contract with a service provider via our site, the information you provide, and any further information requested by the service provider will be held by them for the purposes set out in their individual privacy policies. Once you are contracted to a service provider, we have no control over how they use your personal information or to whom it is disclosed.

##  6\. Rights to Your Personal Data

As a user of compareandsave.com you have the right to request any personal information that we hold on you. If any of this information is incorrect we will make amendments and confirm changes to you. Please write to us at the address below should you wish to make a request under the terms of the Data Protection Act 1998 (DPA):

**Data Protection Officer  
** **Freedom Marketing Limited  
** **Colchester Centre  
** **Hawkins Road  
** **Colchester  
** **CO2 8JX  
**

All you need to do is send two forms of ID that display your name, address and/or date of birth and a cheque for the statutory admin fee of £10.00 made payable to Freedom Marketing Limited. This charge falls under the DPA to cover admin costs.

If you have any queries about data protection and this privacy policy please feel free to write to the Data Protection Office using the above address.
